Finding Aid for George Lockley papers, 1861-1866 [microform]
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
George Lockley papers [microform] 1861-1866
Lockley, George, b. 1836.
1 microfilm reel
86689 mf 301c
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
The collection was the gift of Mr. and Mrs. Russell F. Donker (donor no. 5862 ).
No further additions to the papers are expected.
The collection is open to research; for reasons of preservation; no access is permitted to the originals.
Originals of this collection are also available at the Bentley Historical Library.
George Lockley was a resident of Ann Arbor, Michigan. During the Civil War, he served as a colonel in the 1st Michigan Infantry.
The Lockley papers include diaries, transcriptions of diaries, maps of battles in which he participated, including the first and second battles of Bull Run, Antietam, Fredericksburg, Chancellorsville and Gettysburg. Also included is a copy of a report by Lt. Colonel Benjamin D. Pritchard on the capture of Jefferson Davis and other Confederate leaders by the 4th Michigan Cavalry. There are also a few photographs and miscellaneous materials from his wartime service.
Subjects:
Antietam, Battle of, Md., 1862.; Bull Run, 1st Battle of, Va., 1861.; Bull Run, 2nd Battle of, Va., 1862.; Chancellorsville, Battle of, Chancellorsville, Va., 1863.; Davis, Jefferson, 1808-1889.; Fredericksburg, Battle of, Fredericksburg, Va., 1862.; Gettysburg, Battle of, Gettysburg, Pa., 1863.; Lockley, George, b. 1836.; Pritchard, Benjamin Dudley, 1835-1907.; United States. Army. Michigan Cavalry Regiment, 4th (1862-1865); United States. Army. Michigan Infantry Regiment, 1st (1861-1865); United States. Army. Michigan Infantry Regiment, 1st (1861). Company B.; United States--History--Civil War, 1861-1865.
Subjects - Visual Materials:
Lockley, Amelia.; Lockley, George, b. 1836.; Military uniforms.; Soldiers--American.; United States. Army. Michigan Infantry Regiment, 1st (1861-1865); United States--History--Civil War, 1861-1865.
Genre Terms:
Diaries.; Photographs.
- Diaries
  - April 1861-August 1863 (Reel 1)
  - September-December 1862 (Reel 1)
  - 1863 (Reel 1)
  - May-October 1863 (Reel 1)
  - October 1863-February 1864 (Reel 1)
  - March-October 1864 (Reel 1)
  - October 1864-May 1865 (Reel 1)
  - June 1865-January 1866 (Reel 1)
  - Diary transcripts (Reel 1)
- Other materials
  - Civil War Diary of George Lockley (galleys of book) (Reel 1)
  - Maps of Civil War battles in which George Lockley participated (Reel 1)
  - Account (copy) by Lt. Colonel Benjamin D. Pritchard on the capture of Jefferson Davis and other Confederate leaders by the 4th Michigan Cavalry, 11 pp. (Reel 1)
  - Civil War miscellanea, including key to diary code (Reel 1)
  - Photographs: portraits of Lockley in uniform; also portraits of his wife, Amelia Lockley, and of other soldiers; and copy prints of Civil War documents. (Reel 1)